"Very careful, because the moment
there is a single drop of blood,
we’ll stop being Robin Hoods
and we’ll simply become sons of a bitch."
Rio, Rio!
Holy shit, man!
Holy shit, Tokyo!
This couldn’t have started,
fucking worse, man!
Jesus Christ!
Fuck!
Let’s see...
Paula, you need a purple flower there.
Paula.
I don’t understand
why dad can’t come tomorrow
-to my birthday party.
-I already told you, Paula.
A judge took custody away from him
and now it’s me
-who will take care of you.
-It wasn’t a judge.
-Really?
-No.
And who was that?
It was you. You don’t want him
to come to my party.
Am I right, grandma?
Huh... Well, listen,
dad and mum are upset now.
-Things will get better, you’ll see.
-Mum, please!
Inspector.
"Raquel, I know it’s your day off,
but there’s a robbery with hostages.
The robbers tried to go out
with the money, but they couldn’t.
They’ve hurt two officers.
It’s in the Fábrica Nacional
de Moneda y Timbre.
I want you to take care
of the negotiation."
-Send me a car.
-"It’s parked outside."
Explain me what the fucking shit was that!
Explain me what the fuck was that!
Are you crazy?
8 HOURS OF ROBBERY
-You’ve riddled two policemen!
-Calm down.
A fucking officer appeared and shot at me.
What would you have done,
would you have spat at him?
-Fucking shit!
-What can you do, man,
what can you do,
stick to the fucking plan, jeez,
we went over it 400 million times.
FRIDAY 6:25 P.M.
We said that,
we weren’t going to shoot anyone.
-I fell, blocked by the impacts...
-Shut up!
We also covered you,
but shooting at the ground,
not point-blank to their bodies.
They’re taking away the injured officers.
Are the phones connected?
Cut off any wireless or radio signal.
Let’s pass to analogue.
Call the Professor.
What are you wearing?
-What happened?
-"Two officers were hurt."
Who shot?
"Tokyo."
Connect the Professor’s cameras.
"A bullet went near Rio and Tokyo shot."
It seems they have an affair.
Put her through.
-"What?"
-Is that true?
-So you have an affair with Rio?
-What the fuck are you saying?
No.
The love of my life died because of me,
the last thing I would think about
is having an affair with a kid.
"I shot to protect myself and my partner."
And, Mr Professor,
even if you think them over a lot, things
"don’t always turn out
the way you expect."
-What happened?
-They opened a vault
in the Fábrica de Moneda
to take the latest banknotes.
-Why didn’t the alarms set off?
-There was a manual alarm,
-we guess it must have been a worker.
-How many hostages?
It’s impossible to know,
the museum was open.
Give me a number.
Confirmed: 35 workers, 11 security guards
and 17 children from the British School.
-What the fuck were they doing there?
-It was a school visit.
-Do the media know about it yet?
-No, not yet.
-The robbers?
-We don’t know yet.
We’re getting images
from the nearby shops.
-He’s lost a lot of blood.
-How many can they be?
Four went outside, we think six at least.
-Weapons?
-We know they have at least three M16.
-And they’re extremely aggressive.
-The GEO are already here.
Yes, they came here in the first place.
Please, give me some good news.
The officers who were shot are alive.
Thank goodness.
Let’s go.
What’s up with the cameras
inside the building?
-Where’s the signal?
-There’s no signal.
-Why not?
-There isn’t, I don’t know.
They must have broken or diverted it.
We’re working on it.
What about the network?
They cut off the optical fibre,
we can’t hack them.
Listen carefully, all of you,
Police, Civil Protection,
I want all the phones switched off.
We’re going to use the repeater
on the roof of the building
in case they make any calls.
I want any phone signal
in the whole perimeter
to get straight here.
Okay, I want
all the listening analysts here,
in two seconds. All right?
-Do we have the building layout?
-I’m considering a possible intervention.
Intense "volluto".
The public servants are
well taken care of.
What the fuck are you doing?
We have some free time.
They have to set up the camp,
send us a drone,
find the building layout.
We must give them some time
so they organize.
Hey, why did Tokyo say
you’re not together?
Because we’re not.
Then why did I hear
every night her headboard
banging like a slide hammer?
Is she learning to dance samba
-at 5 in the morning?
-I don’t know,
haven’t got a fucking clue. Don’t know
if she dances or she’s restless.
Tell me, do I look like a prick to you?
Do you think you can lie to me non-stop?
I’m kidding.
I would have fucked her, too.
In fact, I might try to.
I think you’re wrong.
I’m very serious with her.
Very serious?
But, seriously as having a garden
and doing home improvement
-on Sundays?
-That’s right.
And fill it with children.
Sit down.
Look, boy, women will give you sex and fun
because... they’re programmed
to subdue so you impregnate them.
Later you’ll cease to exist.
During childbirth you’ll notice that.
Childbirth must be the most exciting event
in a father’s life.
In childbirth, whatever comes out
from between her legs
is a nuclear warhead
that will destroy everything.
First of all, the wonderful cave
where you used to put your thingy
will never be the same again.
And while she’s cursing you
and asks for the epidural,
she’ll have a bowel movement.
Do you know what she means by that?
That she’ll never be a sexy woman again.
And that from now on
that sucker is becoming
the centre of the universe.
They’re all the same.
Believe me, I’ve had five divorces.
Do you know what five divorces are?
Five times I believed in love.
What fucking shit
have you got in your head?
Huh?
How the hell could Professor
put you in charge?
Due to my sensitivity dealing with people.
Take the little lamb out of the group
and take her to an office.
And don’t leave her alone.
If she needs to change her towel,
stand next to her.
Okay.
We’ll be back in 30 minutes.
30 minutes, Denver.
Excuse me.
Huh... Well, I’m going to jog for a while,
to stretch my legs a bit.
Do it. You have enough space.
Learning a language
is much easier than it seems,
but you have to lay semantics aside.
Let’s go.
Don’t worry. I’m taking you elsewhere
so you can rest, that’s all.
Okay?
Raquel, all the communications
we keep from the inside
must be done from this phone
or the radio, not cell phones, okay?
Put me through with the interior,
I want to talk to the robbers.
Ángel, what the fuck
is colonel Prieto doing here?
I don’t know. I don’t know.
There are people shooting their guns
in the place where money is made.
Don’t you think Intelligence
should be aware?
Calling the Fábrica
de Moneda y Timbre, Raquel.
Boss, call to the interior in progress.
"Hello."
-Good afternoon.
-"I’m Raquel Murillo,"
the inspector in charge of the robbery.
Who am I talking to?
"To the robber in charge of the assault."
-He’s got a voice changer.
-Cleaning the signal.
How are your mates doing?
So far we haven’t had any casualties.
"I’m glad."
"Really, sincerely."
Excuse me, I can’t hear you well.
Yes, I’m sorry about
this hateful metallic voice,
"but you must understand
I have to protect my identity,"
just in case one day you give us
a helicopter and we go to Brazil.
Is that what you want, a helicopter?
"What I want right now
is to negotiate with someone"
who doesn’t give us the runaround,
who doesn’t need to ask a superior,
Intelligence or their mum
to give me a yes or a no.
Then you should talk to the president,
but since he’s busy running the country,
I’ll try to stand in for him,
"if you don’t mind."
-Any further questions?
-"Yes."
What are you wearing?
-Pardon?
-"What are you wearing?
Don’t you think our clothes"
say a lot about our personality?
Look, I have no objection
to answer your question,
but I think I should inform you
"this conversation is being heard
by several members
of the UDEF, the UIT, the CNI"
and their liaison office, the chief
of the GEO and some other officers.
In that case, I think I should say hello
and introduce myself.
It’s nice to meet you.
"I regret I can’t tell you my name,
but you can call me"
Professor, everybody calls me so.
Hello. I’m Ángel,
Deputy Inspector of Police.
Nice to meet you, Ángel.
How are you doing?
-"Hello, good morning."
-Good morning.
Hello, how are you?
Very well. I’m very well,
thanks a lot. And you?
After this emotional moment, tell me,
-what do you want?
-Time...
"to try and clarify things.
Listen to me, Inspector.
We couldn’t go out only for
a matter of seconds, but we’re"
perfectly ready to defend ourselves,
"so try to avoid
any kind of intervention."
-Can I trust you?
-Of course.
But in order for me to trust you,
you must make a gesture towards me.
Release those children from the school,
they’re minors.
Everything will be much better that way.
But, Inspector, you still
haven’t told me what you’re wearing.
A grey suit jacket, a blue shirt,
"black high heel boots and..."
Well, I think so far that’s enough, right?
"So I can picture you a lot better."
But, Inspector, a suit jacket for women
can have a skirt or trousers,
"so I’ll ask you that next time you are"
a bit more specific.
Let me think about your request.
Tell me, what sort of lunatic
with 60 hostages
thinks about teasing his negotiator?
No, he’s too calm to be a lunatic.
I want helicopters flying
all day long over their heads!
No food, water or any other type
of request. Am I clear?
Excuse me, Inspector.
Just because you leave them without
dessert I don’t think they’ll surrender.
Both the chief of the GEO,
here present, and me
believe it’s necessary
an immediate intervention.
If they wanted a massacre
like in Moscow’s Opera House,
they’d have called you straightaway,
but unfortunately
you’re here only to opine and bug.
Please, Inspector,
don’t be on the defensive.
I’m here to help you.
I know you’re not going
through your best moment.
If you mean my period, it’s not the case,
but thanks for asking.
I mean the complaint of ill-treatment
you’ve filed against your ex-husband.
Wow, I see Intelligence
did their homework.
There isn’t a single room
where they don’t stick their nose, right?
Internal Affairs also do it.
They think you’ve brought a false report.
Your ex-husband has rebuilt his life
both personally and professionally
in the police,
but some women don’t always turn the page.
Look, I don’t know if you’re miserable
or... just stupid.
If somebody’s interested
in my personal life,
I must say
that matter has been totally got past
and it’s in the hands of a judge.
Thanks for your sensitivity, colonel.
There’s an incoming call
in the museum’s repeater.
-Record it.
-Yes, we’re recording.
Turn up the volume. Silence, please!
-"Why aren’t you coming for dinner?
-I’m working.
My apologies to your mother and sister.
-Why aren’t you coming?"
There’s a good mess here.
My apologies to them. Believe me.
-Don’t yell at me, honey, please.
-Almansa!
I have to go, okay, sweetheart?
Okay, I love you so much. Bye.
Cut.
It’s Almansa.
Why did you bring me here?
No, don’t worry.
They brought me here to protect you.
Just that.
When you get naked, please,
put on the red overalls.
Fine.
What if it goes wrong?
-What’s up if it goes wrong?
-Well, darling,
the usual things: back in prison,
the cigarette in the yard,
four langoustines at Christmas,
-the vis-à-vis, sometimes.
-A real luxury.
It’s worst if it goes well. What the fuck
are we going to do with so much dough?
I’ll buy a Maserati,
the colour of a clear blue sky, huh?
-Sure.
-And a martial arts gym.
I can see it.
And a bar, with three floors, huh?
With loudspeakers
that make your ears bleed.
-Boom, boom, pam, pim pam pum.
-Sure.
-He’s got enough with three million.
-And a pair of lungs for you,
because you fucked them up in the mine.
Are you spending your money
on a pair of lungs?
Good heavens!
And where the fuck
are you going to find some lungs?
Some people sell their kidneys.
There must be people who sell lungs,
I think.
Well, I... a winery in Provence.
A hundred hectares of vineyards
to cultivate my own wine,
-oak casks...
-But, man, you can go to any supermarket
and buy whatever
fucking bottle you want.
-Why do you want a winery?
-For the art.
Well, I want an island.
-I want another one.
-And a third one.
-Three’s a crowd.
-An archipelago.
No, I want a little island
that has a huge house,
you know?, with a small balcony
next to the sea.
I’ll wake up every morning
and dive into the water.
At last someone’s intelligent.
I think some of us have to sort
some things out first, right?
Well, at least I have.
And then, with what’s left,
I’ll buy a plane.
-And I’ll pilot it.
-You could have a hot pilot.
No, you don’t get it,
the best thing is to show off
at the man at the control tower:
"I need a runway
to go to Broadway."
If we buy all those things
let’s say for a price...
I don’t know, an expensive price,
a very expensive price.
However, we’d still have
a lot of money left.
If we’re robbing big,
dream big.
I’d record an album, singing "corridos".
And my face on the cover.
You’ll be like Bertín Osborne,
but 30 kilos fatter.
-Whoa!
-What are you saying?
Bertín sings "rancheras",
I said "corridos",
it’s very different.
Show him what a "corrido" is, dad.
Show him.
-No way...
-Come on.
-Come on!
-Come on, man.
-But you love it.
-I’m not going to sing!
-Sing, sing.
-He’s stood up.
"Because I didn’t have your lips
I cried for the first time"
"And I cursed knowing you
to not stop loving you"
"I wanted to make you my wife"
"I looked for luck loveless"
"I took out my gun"
"And fate brought death"
"María, my life, my love"
"I won’t stop loving you"
"I lost you due to bullets"
"You won’t see me again"
Stand up.
Come on, come on.
Take out your masks.
Take out your masks!
What’s the matter?
We’re going to be good.
Something has come up,
but, in spite of helicopters,
I’m aware we’re going
to have some quiet hours
and you’ll be able to rest.
In a few minutes
we’ll give you sleeping bags,
water and a sandwich.
Oh, and let me ask you a favour.
I want you to get naked.
I want to give you red overalls like ours
so you feel more comfortable.
Excuse me, sir,
I don’t want to bother you.
Among these people there are people
with heart conditions,
pregnant women, diabetics, teenagers...
I beg you, please,
release those who are more vulnerable.
I don’t think they can stand
this anguish all night long.
-Do you think you’re fucking Gandhi?
-Denver, calm down.
He’s a friend of mine.
We share our love for cinema.
Take the gun.
I’m not asking you if you want,
I’m telling you to take the gun.
Take the gun. Take the gun.
-And now aim at me.
-No, please.
I’m telling you to aim at me.
A fucking order. Aim at me, jeez.
-Here. Fine.
-No, please.
And now you shoot me.
-Pardon?
-Shoot me.
-Please.
-Please, no!
-Either you shoot me
or I’ll shoot you. I give you ten seconds.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine...
They’re fake, Arturito,
but you did very well.
You did very well.
It’s a present, you can keep it.
Now we’re giving you some fake guns.
In a few hours
we’ll need your cooperation.
As you’ve seen, the only thing
you have to do is obey.
Trust us... and obey.
Come on, get naked.
Come on.
"What are you wearing?"
Raquel, no walkie-talkie, no phones,
no electronic devices.
We haven’t located
any radiofrequency inside.
Are you telling me they communicate
using an empty yogurt and a string
-so we don’t detect them?
-I don’t know if it’s a yogurt
or it’s a gang of deaf-mutes,
but we can’t find any frequencies.
What the fuck are
those armoured vehicles doing here?
We’re getting in with everything.
That’ll be if I give the order.
I’m in charge but I still haven’t done it.
They’re orders from above.
Is anyone going to tell me
what the fuck is going on here
or do I have to phone
the Minister of Interior Affairs?
-What the fuck is going on?
-Let’s go.
Inside there’s a priority 1 person.
-Do you know what "priority 1" is?
-No.
I’m not with your Intelligence gang,
I don’t know.
They’ll get in. They’ll get in
because we have our little lamb.
Alison Parker.
"Sir Benjamin Parker’s daughter.
he’s the UK ambassador"
and a close friend
to the Queen of England.
That’s why we have no choice
but getting in,
because, if we don’t do it now,
the whole country will know tomorrow.
They’ll think we don’t know.
They’ll think they managed to hide
all that information
from the public opinion.
Today she’s just another hostage,
but tomorrow she’ll be the main bullseye
and all the guns will aim at her head.
Is that what you want? Huh?
That’s why they’ll get in the first night.
And they’ll do it before 04:15 am.
Because at 6:30 begins to get light.
Do you imagine what it’d be
for Spain a hostage crisis
managed by the United Kingdom?
And it’s better
if they don’t hesitate to get in
because then we’ll have more possibilities
to win the first battle.
Inspector Murillo,
we’re getting in now
and we’re taking out that girl alive.
I have to talk to you...
You’ve ignored me all the time.
Shut up, they’ll kill us all
and it’s your fault.
Sorry.
It seems you don’t like
your boss much, right?
How do you know he’s my boss?
Because I know everything about you.
I’ve studied that.
I’ve also seen the pregnancy test
on your table.
And now I guess who the father must be.
He didn’t like the present.
What did he say?
He doesn’t want to deal with it?
It’s not easy saying goodbye to a baby.
What are you going to do?
Abort.
Intervention units 1, 2 and 3, ready.
-We’re getting in.
-Let’s go!
-Come on, come on!
-"Teams 1, 2 and 3, ready."
Now.
Team 1, hidden at the front door.
Watch the flat roof and the high flanks.
Hello?
Berlin,
-they’re getting in.
-There we go.
People, the time has come!
It’s the moment to follow my orders!
Follow us.
"And that’s how the State security forces
did exactly what the Professor
told us they’d do,
only that afternoon, when he said that,
we were in the countryside
and we didn’t have the feeling
they were going to shoot us in the head."
They’ll get in through the four places
they can use to access:
the main door, the load area,
the emergency exit and the rooftop.
Watch the rearguard
of the overtaken doors.
Don’t let anyone out.
But they’ll wait. They’ll wait
for Technical Intervention officers
to examine the place.
They’ll do that from the load access.
Come on, come on.
Come on, they’re already at the door.
Okay?
Insert the periscope.
Let’s go.
Raquel, there’s an incoming call
from one hostage’s phone,
Alison Parker.
"As you know, a group of kidnappers..."
Turn it up.
"We have another listener
on the phone to give us her opinion.
I’m not a listener.
I’m a hostage and I’m kidnapped."
My name’s Alison Parker. I’m the United
Kingdom’s ambassador’s daughter.
-Live, in Onda Cero.
-"I’m calling you"
from the interior
of the Fábrica de Moneda y Timbre.
End that call right now!
-Now! End it now!
-End the call!
We’re dressed just like the kidnappers.
Colonel, we have images.
What the fuck is that?
They gave us guns
and we’re wearing the same masks.
-Enlarge. Stop there.
-Nobody knows who is who.
-He’s got a Browning machine gun.
-Motherfuckers.
If the police come in,
innocents will get hurt.
Entrenched with the hostages,
all with the same clothes.
It’s impossible to know
who they’re going to shoot.
-Don’t get in.
-Stop this, Suárez.
Stop it!
-Don’t get in, for God’s sake.
-Stop it.
Abandon positions. Abort the operation.
Inspector...
Finish what you started, colonel.
I don’t want to have
anything to do with this.
"And that’s how we won our first battle
the first night there,
without entering a combat
and thanks to common sense.
And 20 minutes later...
we started to do what we were there for."
This is the nicest part,
we’re going to work.
With me:
Torres, Sánchez, Biedma,
"Lennon,
Guatsani,
Molina, García,
Domingo, De Gorza, Mateo."
Come on, that way.
"Rodrigo, Molla, Pérez."
Come on.
Listen, I want the machines working
24 hours a day,
as if it was one of Pocholo’s raves.
You know what I mean?
"Every time we stop we’ll lose a million,
so we’re not stopping."
We’ll do the technical amendments
every three hours,
"both from the ink and the offset."
So you know: joy, party and excitement.
"The best paid job ever:
2,400 million euros, maybe more.
It all depended on the time
we could hold on inside."
Oh my goodness! This is wonderful, man!
This is wonderful, "coquinoqui"!
Our money, man!
Jeez!
We’re making our own dough, people!
Can I have a decaf, please?
"Hello. This is Mariví’s
answering machine.
When you hear the beep,
you can leave a message."
Mum, I’ve just finished, it’s six...
-Excuse me, do you have a phone charger?
-No.
Do you want to use mine?
Really? Don’t you mind?
-No.
-Are you sure?
Thanks.
I have to make a couple of calls.
-It’s all right.
-Thanks a lot.